myflcourtaccess.com 2013-05-01

# Florida Courts eFiling Portal

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

Collection of your Personal Information

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal collects personally identifiable information such as, your e-mail address, name, home address, work address and telephone number. The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal also collects anonymous demographic information which is not unique to you such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

In addition, information about your computer hardware and software is automatically collected by Florida Courts E-Filing Portal. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal for operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal website.

Please be advised that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal public message boards that this information may be collected and used by others. Note: the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal does not read any of your private online communications.

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to and from the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal site so that you can understand how those web sites collect, use and share your information. The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal and the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal family of websites.

Use of your Personal Information

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal collects and uses your personal information to operate the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal website and deliver the services you have requested. The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal and its affiliates. The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal may from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email, postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal and are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal tracks websites visited by our customers while utilizing the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal in order to determine what Florida Courts E-Filing Portal services are - most popular. This data is utilized to deliver customized content and advertising within the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal, or the public.

Use of Cookies

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal website uses "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal pages, or register with the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal site or services, a cookie helps the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Florida Courts E-Filing Portal web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal or other web sites you visit.

Security of your Personal Information

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

Changes to this Statement

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal is protecting your information.

Contact Information

The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that The Florida Courts E-Filing Portal has not adhered to this Statement, please contact the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal at [support@myflcourtaccess.com](mailto:support@myflcourtaccess.com "Email Support") . We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.

| | 

News & Information

  * Miami-Dade Emergency Filings follow the same current procedures 

  * Notice: A new filer role for Attorney - Pro Hac Vice has been added to the Florida Courts E-Filing Portal. The registration process is the same as for other Florida Bar attorneys. Prospective registrants are asked to please consult the Florida Bar Process for Pro Hac Vice found on the E-filing Authority Board website. 

  * As of March 1, 2013, "follow-up" copies of efiled documents are no longer required to be sent to the Marion County Clerk's Office. 

  * Highlands County does not accept “blank – proposed” Orders through eFiling. All proposed Orders must be delivered directly to the Clerk of Court Office or to the assigned Judge . 

  * St. Johns County: FRJA 2.525 mandates that any person who e-files a document must file the identical paper document with the clerk, immediately thereafter. This filing is called the “follow-up filing”. It is imperative that every filer print-out and attach their e-mail receipt on top of the follow-up filings. The e-mail receipt will be located in each filer’s “Notifications” tab on the ePortal site. Follow-up filings will continue until all criteria in FRJA 2.525(c)(2)(A-C) have been met. 

  * Miami Dade County no longer requires follow up paper filings as approved by Florida Courts Technology Commission set forth by the Supreme Court
